Hello everyone, I am Zhang Yu-jie, a lecturer in fashion and clothing design at Jiaxin Professional Academy of Technology.
I am very honored to be able to be on the platform Cloud2026 digital fashion academic page,
and to be able to discuss and communicate with friends who are concerned about digital fashion and clothing talent training across the country.
Today, I would like to share the topic of digital clothing talent training as a way to break through.
In recent years, the entire clothing industry has undergone a profound reform.
From traditional paper to suit, to cloth, digital and virtual fashion, and to our AIGC and 3D co-creation,
digitalization and intelligentization are no longer an option, but a must-have for our clothing industry.
Therefore, our school, as a professional school, is gradually rebuilding the transformation of courses and the training system of talents.
Here are some of my personal introductions and awards.
In the past few years, I have been very fortunate to be able to participate in some of the results obtained in the various competitions of 3D.
As a first-tier professional education teacher,
my core idea now is to think about how to cultivate the real needs of the enterprises,
the ones that can be kept and the ones that can be used, and develop good digital clothing talents.
Combining my years of digital teaching experience and our business project experience,
as well as the experience of guiding students to participate in competitions,
I will start my sharing from the following five points.
First of all, the first part is to create a plan to train digital clothing talents in a timely manner.
Then, in this part, the first problem we have to solve is what to teach,
and how to teach it so that it can accurately match the needs of the enterprises.
So, it is very important to grasp its core ability,
and to design and customize the ability of the enterprises.
In the process of deep cooperation with the enterprises,
what I hear the most is that the digital transformation of clothing enterprises is difficult,
the cost is high, and the period is long,
especially for the first-tier employees in the enterprises.
They usually work very hard,
and it is difficult for them to learn 3D digitalization in a systematic way.
However, they can still accept it if they do a small study in the next step.
Therefore, what they lack most now is a comprehensive digital talent that can be directly used.
Then, in connecting with the classes of our enterprises,
I will clarify with the enterprises a knowledge map of the students they need.
Then, on the right side is a knowledge map that I created.
It includes a hard skill that needs to be learned,
including digital modeling, clothing sample adjustment,
the clothing sample rendering mentioned by our experts,
and the production of these fabrics.
These are all hard skills.
Then, what about some of the soft skills?
For example, the ability to report the exhibition,
the ability to organize and coordinate,
the ability to communicate with each other,
and the hardness of eating and drinking.
Then, by discussing this ability map with the enterprises,
we can make changes.
In the course, the knowledge structure of learning
will change the mobility of teaching.
So, in this part, we will proceed in this way.
At the same time, we will invite the enterprises to participate deeply
in the arrangement and customization of our 3D courses and systems.
For example, at the beginning of our collaboration class,
we will meet the top-level clothing enterprises
to invite our enterprises,
and some of the people in charge of the Human Resources Department
to participate in the customization of our talent training.
For example, on the upper right side,
it is a total of 10 courses of the Asian class.
Among them, 3D occupies 5% of the concept.
It only needs to understand what the 3D is doing.
For example, the silk class,
it needs more 3D modeling content,
because it has an external 3D business.
So, one is 5% and the other is 14%.
The quantity difference between the number of classes is about 100.
So, for enterprises that require higher students' modeling ability,
we will make appropriate adjustments in the course.
Simply put, what does the enterprise need?
We focus on what we need to teach it.
What does the position require?
We focus on what to add.
The second part,
which is to participate in an enterprise project,
and then to get a real project experience,
by introducing our enterprises to a real project,
so that students can grow in the real world.
I have always believed that
it is better not to let students do a real project
than to say it 10,000 times in class.
When they experience the difficulty of actual combat,
it can stimulate their learning positivity.
For example,
we have long-term deep cooperation with the local Longtou enterprises in Jiaxing.
In teaching,
we have moved the real orders,
the public service requirements,
and the regulations directly into our class.
Here is a real case of an enterprise with a certain difficulty.
Its public service details are involved in a lot of things,
such as the collar,
the waist belt,
the private line,
the invisible square buckle,
the pin,
the waist buckle,
and so on.
These structures are relatively complex.
There is also a backpack that can be paired with it.
On the front,
we can see that there is a three-dimensional cover.
You can see that this is a three-dimensional cover.
Among the samples given by the enterprises,
the cover is actually incomplete.
Our students need to add some independent samples
through their own operations.
At the same time,
the requirements of the enterprises for the texture of the fabric
also need to be very restored.
So when students think they are not doing practice questions,
but when completing a product that the enterprise really wants to deliver,
they will strictly follow the standards of the enterprise
to complete the entire process.
So this model brings three obvious changes.
The first is that the students' learning power is stronger.
Knowing that their learning skills can make money directly,
and can directly go to school,
they are very happy.
And then the ability to do it is also rapidly improved.
To analyze the structure of the sample plate,
to analyze which sample plate corresponds to each part.
In graduation,
they can directly connect to the real project of our enterprise.
At the same time,
they can also adapt to the rhythm of our workplace in advance,
and cultivate their rigorous, detailed and efficient work habits.
At the same time,
for the enterprises,
when we introduce these real projects to the course,
they can really respond to the students' movements in the actual battle,
forming a double link.
Then the third part,
I want to say that
we have established
a model of our listening,
feedback,
and optimization of a dynamic teaching model.
Teaching is not a single output.
Then we try to build a set of
two-way feedback teaching model
that covers our returnees and online returnees.
When facing our returnees,
we will interact online.
For example,
we will carry out a questionnaire in our study hall,
and an analysis of the words and sentences,
to collect the students' real learning feelings
or their pain points.
For example,
in this feedback,
we will find that
there are many high-level difficulties
such as wearable problems,
and some details,
such as the belt cover,
and some pants pockets,
these places,
they feel very difficult.
Then there are also,
for example,
a model of a walking show,
a simulation animation,
not smooth,
he feels very troubled about these problems.
So for these problems,
I will immediately adjust
the focus of our next class,
which is
how to improve the performance of our students,
for example,
wearable,
he will have a modified special practice,
or strengthen,
we have some,
especially the sewing line type,
if it changes incorrectly,
it will cause his clothes to be made
different from the effect we made.
Including some of the parameters
of the board conflict adjustment,
and this walking show,
some of his wearable problems,
through these trainings,
to reduce the threshold of our teaching,
to be able to gradually
let the students gradually learn
our skills,
how to use our skills,
and so on.
In order to learn
our overall
3D modeling process.
The second is
to connect the 3D modelers
who graduated from us
in the enterprise
to their enterprise projects.
In the course of our teaching process,
we did not send this student
out of the campus,
just ignore him,
or will continue to follow up
on these students.
For example,
some of the problems
he encountered in the enterprise
will also be adjusted
for him.
For example,
this student
encountered some problems
in his position
in the enterprise.
For example,
he sometimes needs
to make some adjustments
in his position.
Just like what I just said,
the enterprise needs to be
flexible and flexible
in terms of talent.
This student,
for example,
in the 3D business,
he needs to relax
for a while.
He needs to participate
in other business
after he enters.
He can also
achieve a very good
ability of coordination
in the 3D business.
So,
this student
is able to
communicate with other students
in this process.
So,
in this process,
students,
for example,
have emotions
or difficulties,
we will also
teach them
in the same way.
At the same time,
we can also
communicate with
the students
online.
We can also
communicate with them
and bring the needs
of the first-line position
back to our classroom
to update our teaching content.
For example,
this student,
after he enters the enterprise,
he not only needs
to do 3D related,
but he also needs
to learn AIGC
in order to
be able to
communicate with
other students.
So,
in this course,
we will integrate
and let our students
have the ability
to follow
the first line
of our industry.
The fourth part,
like before,
when we were
doing some
training,
many students
are easy to
get lost
and can't
do it.
They feel that
they don't have the heart
to do it.
So, in this part,
I want to tell you
that the project
drives the students
to learn
how to do it.
So,
before,
in 2024,
I have won
a gold medal
for the three-dimensional
digital restoration
of traditional Chinese clothing.
So,
in the course,
I put this experience
into the course
and
told the students
about
the idea
of this project
and
also
introduced
how I
won
this gold medal.
For example,
from the first step,
what do we do first,
what do we do next,
step by step,
and so on.
I also
send these materials
to the students
in other places
before.
Then,
the students
see the lecture
I made
and I can,
for example,
the teacher can get this prize,
the teacher gives this thing to him,
he will naturally feel
that
I am still a little confident.
Then,
in the process of doing this,
you can see
this is
a five-stage
South Tang
fairy tale painting.
The whole
clothing
decoration
and the whole
layout
are all made by
the students.
From the
early
historical
research,
to the
production of
human body
and body,
to the
processing of
the clothing,
and the
fabric
stickers,
the details of the
craftsmanship,
the patterns,
and the
final virtual
display
and rendering.
In the whole
complete project,
the students
can turn
this fragmented
into an exhibition
of the whole course.
You can see
this is
an exhibition corner
of our school.
Through
such an exhibition,
of course,
we also have
a digital
boy.
Every year,
there will be a
digital boy fashion show
so that our students'
design
can be seen
and recognized.
Next,
I want to show you
a
B-team team
I brought.
They completed
the restoration of
this Songdai
听软图.
They also
restored
the
decoration
of
our
characters,
the production
of
equipment,
and the
editing of
our
accessories.
It includes
the efforts
of the students.
So,
thank you very much
to this platform
for giving us
this opportunity
so that our
students can also
be seen.
Please enjoy it.
Thank you.
I don't know if it's possible.
I was wondering if it was possible to connect with a Japanese character in the middle.
I found it interesting.
I like the visual.
I think I'd like to try it.
It's a good idea.
I want to try it.
I think it's a good idea.
I like it.
I want to try it.
I think it's a good idea.
I like it.
The children have their own research, and in the process of this research, they also get a lot of improvement through the practice.
The whole project is designed and produced by them, including the presentation method behind it.
I think they did this project with great care.
In the end, the children can take part in the learning process.
It has been a goal of the school to create an independent school for students.
When the students have the skills and experiences above,
we will take the opportunity to learn more with the help of these advanced skills.
Thank you.
to check the results of our students
and actively guide them to participate in these competitions.
For example, I led them to participate in two
Chinese traditional three-dimensional clothing restoration innovative design competitions.
This competition is attended by the entire industry,
teachers and students.
In the second year, our students only received an excellent award.
In the third year, they received two bronze medals.
So their progress is also very great.
In addition, we also participated in a gold medal competition in 2025.
It is a fashion digital design competition of AIGC and 3D.
They won a national gold medal.
When the student took the award certificate,
looked at his or her virtual work and was seen by others,
this confidence and motivation
can't be replaced by any lecture in any class.
In addition, the fifth piece I want to share with you is
multi-level rules, including the standards of enterprises and industries.
Through our business experts' lectures and special lectures,
we help students to understand the needs of digitalization of clothing more closely.
At the same time, we also connect all the official level tests and so on,
so that students can understand more deeply
the standards and requirements of the clothing industry and the position,
so that students can make a change from our classroom to the workplace.
In terms of software operation,
it is not just to point out our tools
and follow this process,
step by step,
but to learn to solve complex difficulties
and independently complete the design of our full process.
From the industry,
to know it,
and to know it,
to understand the 3D logic behind our clothing industry,
to become a real designer,
technical expert,
and clothing digital talent in the industry.
On the right side,
we have students from our classroom cases
to the transformation of our business projects.
So, everyone,
our clothing digitalization channel,
day-to-day business,
technology is constantly updating,
and technology is constantly upgrading.
The original intention of our training talents does not change.
In summary,
the following four sentences are
that we should be talented in teaching,
and should not deviate from the practicality of students,
and should not deviate from the needs of our enterprises
in the integration of production and education.
At the same time,
we should listen to feedback,
and should not deviate from the changes in the industry.
We should drive the project,
and should not deviate from our practical growth.
In the future,
digital technology will deeply enrich the clothing industry.
AI,
3D,
virtual fashion,
digital transformation
will bring more possibilities.
So I also look forward to
working with you,
teachers,
industry partners,
and co-workers
to contribute to our clothing's new power,
so that our ideas of
art,
innovation,
and business
can become reality from ideas.
My sharing ends here.
Thank you very much for listening.
I also hope that you can communicate more and guide more.
Thank you.